Ada Peirce McCormick papers, 1881-1978 (bulk 1920-1974)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VII: Business Activities, 1939-1968
  - Mexican Contest, 1944-1945
    - Mexican contest, contestants. 1944 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Mexican contest, entries. 1944 (Box 98, Folder 12-14)
    - Mexican contest, entries. 1944 (Box 99, Folder 1-4)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1939-1953
    - Advice and criticisms regarding Letter. 1943-1949 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Bookstore sales. 1943 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Businesses. 1943-1950 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Comments on Letter by Isabella Greenway King and Margaret Sanger. 1947 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Copyrights. 1942-1952 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence. 1939-1943 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence. 1944-1945 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence. 1946-1949 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, APM to authors. 1947-1950 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, APM to authors. 1951-1953 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Cover ideas for Letter. No Date (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Definition of Letter by staff. 1946-1949 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Expenditures. 1942-1943 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Form letters to various groups. 1943-1947 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Gandhi, Nehru and Schweitzer. 1949 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Junior authors group, visit to Letter. 1947 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Legal Matters. 1942-1943 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Letter employee records. 1942-1949 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Letter employees, compiled. 1949 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Letter no. 1--make-up dummy. 1943 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Letter no. 10 (never published)--dummy. No Date (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Letter no. 10, dummy, galleys, proofs. 1948-1953 (Box 100, Folder 12-13)
    - Letter staff. 1943-1950 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Letter stationary. No Date (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Letter to Mexican magazines. 1943 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - List of book reviews, editorials, and reprints. No Date (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript policy. 1945-1947 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript s about APM and Letter. 1946 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Negroes. 1943-1952 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - News agencies handling Letter. 1943-1947 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - Opinions of Letter, university class. 1946 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Permission to reprint. 1942-1945 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - Sermon by Ida M. Tarbell. No Date (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - Tax case. 1949-1953 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - Tax case, Internal Revenue Service. 1953 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - Upham, Maxine, reorganization ideas for Letter. 1946-1953 (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - Working guide and procedures. No Date (Box 101, Folder 15)
    - Write-ups on APM and Letter. 1944-1952 (Box 101, Folder 16)
  - Subscribers, 1942-1953
    - Circulation records. 1946-1948 (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - First 100 Subscribers. 1943 (Box 101, Folder 18)
    - Gift subscriptions. 1943-1944 (Box 101, Folder 19)
    - Letters to Subscribers. 1943-1950 (Box 101, Folder 20)
    - List of Subscribers. 1942-1945 (Box 101, Folder 21)
    - List of subscribers, geographic. 1944 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - List of subscribers, geographic. 1945, 1953 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Responses to subscribers' letters. 1943 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Subscribers to check against divident list. No Date (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Subscribers to Letter Book Club. 1951-1952 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Subscribers to whom dividends being sent. 1945-1951 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Subscription order cards. No Date (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Susbscriptions, exchange with Letter. 1942-1945 (Box 102, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Poetry and Drawings, 1915-1971
  Contains assorted poems and sketches in ink and pencil. APM sometimes used Mary Hayford and Charity Howard as pen names for her poetry.
  - APM, poet and artist. 1925 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - APM poetry, children. ca. 1924 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - APM poetry, God, truth. No Date (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - APM poetry, love. 1922-1944 (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - APM poetry, miscellaneous. 1924-1971 (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - APM poetry, Susan Ryerson Patterson. 1925-1944 (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - APM drawings, Associated Press. 1950 (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - APM drawings, Fred McCormick and Waldo Peirce. No Date (Box 102, Folder 16)
  - APM drawings, General Semantics Conference. 1949 (Box 102, Folder 17)
  - APM drawings, Goethe Bicentennial, Aspen, Colorado. 1949 (Box 102, Folder 18)
  - APM drawings, locals (includes partial index). No Date (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - APM drawings, miscellaneous (includes index). No Date (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - APM drawings, miscellaneous (includes index). No Date (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - APM drawings, miscellaneous (some published in Letter). No Date (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - APM drawings, Tucsonans (includes index). No Date (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - APM drawings, used in Letter. No Date (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - APM drawings, Writers' Conference. 1949 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Silhouettes. No Date (Box 103, Folder 7)
- Series IX: Photographs, ca. 1887-1974
  Contains black and white, and color images. The bulk of the photographs document the McCormick family and friends, and APM's involvement with Letter, its staff and activities. Includes some negatives.
  - Anderson, Sherwood. 1934 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Award to Arizona Daily Wildcat. 1963 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Buck, Pearl. 1965 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Cabot, Richard. No Date (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - d'Autremont family. No Date (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Day, Dorothy. No Date (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Women's Club. 1966 (Box 103, Folder 14)
  - Houses, 1408 and 1410 E. 1st Street. No Date (Box 103, Folder 15)
  - Houses, 111 Olive Rd. No Date (Box 103, Folder 16)
  - Letter exhibits, Arizona State Fair. 1947 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Letter exhibits, Miscellaneous photographs. 1945-1948 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Letter exhibits, Pima county fair. 1948 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Letter Magazine open house. 1948 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - McCormick, Byron. No Date (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Pandit, Madame Vifaya Lakshimi. 1945 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Party for Elizabeth Congdon. 1965 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, APM. ca. 1890s-1920s (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous. ca. 1930s-1973 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, APM and staff. No Date (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, FCM, staff and friends. ca. 1880s-1966 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, McCormick home and office. No Date (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Sanger, Margaret. ca. 1930s (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - Schweitzer, Albert. No Date (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Science Fair Awards, University of Arizona. 1956-1958 (Box 104, Folder 15)
  - Stephan, Ruth, party for Lohia. 1964 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Stephan, Ruth, poetry center. 1960 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Tarbell, Ida M. No Date (Box 105, Folder 3-5)
  - Tucson Advertising Club. ca. 1965 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Tucson Public Library, Young Authors' Club. No Date (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - University Pastors Fellowship. ca. 1963 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Weld, Philippa. 1958-1962 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Webster, George (slaying and burial). 1957 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Women's Medical Association. 1950 (Box 105, Folder 11)
- Series X: Teacher Files, 1913-1942
  : Consists of correspondence, newspaper clippings, course outlines, and scrapbooks. The material reflects APM's teaching experiences in schools and organizational settings, especially her courses on marriage and the art of living.
  - APM to Williamsport (PA) Board of Religious Education. 1923 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Bucknell University. 1927 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Camp Fire Girls. 1923-1926 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Camp Fire Girls, responses to APM course. 1923 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Garland School of Homemaking. 1926-1927 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Mansfield Normal School. 1926-1929 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Marriage Course Outline. ca, 1923, 1942 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous material. 1925-1927 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Ogontz School. 1927-1928 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Parent-Teacher Association. ca. 1933 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Playground Teacher, Bangor, Maine. 1913-1914 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Pocono Peoples College (Camp Fire courses). 1925-1926 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Pocono Peoples College, Fred McCormick correspondence. 1925 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook: "The Art of Living. " ca. 1920s (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - YMCA and YWCA, Lecture on Marriage. 1936 (Box 106, Folder 15)
- Series XI: Biographical Files, 1915-1976
  The bulk of material consists of news clippings and articles about APM and Letter Magazine and related correspondence. The series also contains awards, certificates, and commentaries on the activities of APM. Some of the material overlaps and duplicates items found elsewhere in the collection.
  - APM and FCM wedding. 1915 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - APM Confirmation. 1917 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous news clippings. 1927-1967 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Obituary of Anna Hayford Peirce. 1928 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - APM lectures in Tucson. 1930 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - I.M. Tarbell lectures on biography, APM funded. 1931 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - APM vs. Crenshaw Divorce Bill. 1931 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - "Exit the Cook" article. 1931 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - APM on horseback. 1932 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous. 1932-1955 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - APM entertains winners of Ella Lyman Cabot Cup. 1938 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - League of American Writers. 1940 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Fighting Funds for Finland, Inc. 1940 (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Air raid shelters. 1940-1942 (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - APM advertisement, "What is America Worth to You?" 1941 (Box 107, Folder 15)
  - Negro U.S.O., APM's open letter. 1942 (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Arizona Civil Defense Coordinating Council. 1942 (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - Writers' War Board. 1942 (Box 107, Folder 18)
  - "Let Us Talk About India." 1942 (Box 107, Folder 19)
  - American Woman's Voluntary Service. 1942 (Box 107, Folder 20)
  - War Production Board. 1942 (Box 107, Folder 21)
  - "India, the Time for Mediation is Now." 1942 (Box 107, Folder 22)
  - APM clipping. 1943 (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - APM review. 1943 (Box 107, Folder 24)
  - APM clipping. 1943 (Box 107, Folder 25)
  - Race relations. 1943 (Box 107, Folder 26)
  - Letter. 1943 (Box 107, Folder 27)
  - APM letter to The Atlantial. 1943 (Box 107, Folder 28)
  - "Fellowship of Prayer." 1943 (Box 107, Folder 29)
  - Letter Award. 1944 (Box 107, Folder 30)
  - APM debates Wade Church. 1944 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Letter honors Sidney F. Pattison. 1944 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - The Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - APM on Letter. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - APM on jury. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - APM speaks to Girl Scouts. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Article on Letter Magazine. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Article on Letter Magazine. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Interview on KVOA. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - APM editorial in Deseret News. 1945 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - APM lecture on matrimony. 1946 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Bangor Daily News article about APM. 1946 (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - The Land. 1946 (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Article on Letter Magazine. 1946 (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Editorial in The Presbyterian. 1947 (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Editorial in Books Abroad. 1947 (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Letter exhibit. 1947 (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - APM lectures on Kinsey. 1948 (Box 108, Folder 18)
  - Articles on Letter Magazine. 1948 (Box 108, Folder 19)
  - Letter Award. 1948 (Box 108, Folder 20)
  - Writer's Digest article on APM. 1948 (Box 108, Folder 21)
  - Jailers Institute. 1949 (Box 108, Folder 22)
  - Kinsey Report. 1949 (Box 108, Folder 23)
  - Aspen Times article on APM. < unitdate>1949 (Box 108, Folder 24)
  - APM at Crime Conference. 1949 (Box 108, Folder 25)
  - APM on Albert Schweitzer. 1949 (Box 108, Folder 26)
  - APM radio silhouette. 1950 (Box 108, Folder 27)
  - Arizona Education Association. 1951 (Box 108, Folder 28)
  - Article about APM. 1951 (Box 108, Folder 29)
  - APM lecture to Hadassah. 1951 (Box 108, Folder 30)
  - Character-Intelligence Book Club. 1951 (Box 108, Folder 31)
  - Letter awards to American Scientist. 1952 (Box 108, Folder 32)
  - Certificates, miscellaneous. 1952-1971 (Box 108, Folder 33)
  - APM opposes Leopold parole. 1953 (Box 108, Folder 34)
  - KVOA radio interview. 1954 (Box 108, Folder 35)
  - Character-Intelligence Researchers. 1954 (Box 108, Folder 36)
  - Little Chapel of All Nations. 1954 (Box 108, Folder 37)
  - American Legion Award. 1955 (Box 108, Folder 38)
  - Article on the Little Chapel of All Nations. 1957 (Box 108, Folder 39)
  - APM appointed: AZ Library, Board of Curators. 1957 (Box 108, Folder 40)
  - APM receives University of Arizona Medallion. 1960 (Box 108, Folder 41)
  - Article about APM in Arizona Church Record. 1960 (Box 108, Folder 42)
  - Newspaper Association Awards. 1962 (Box 108, Folder 43)
  - APM's 75th Birthday. 1963 (Box 108, Folder 44)
  - Pearl Buck party. 1965 (Box 108, Folder 45)
  - League of Women Voters. 1966 (Box 108, Folder 46)
  - University of Arizona Certificate of Merit. 1966 (Box 108, Folder 47)
  - Science fair. 1969 (Box 108, Folder 48)
  - Miss Arizona Pageant. 1969 (Box 108, Folder 49)
  - Article on Letter Magazine. 1974 (Box 108, Folder 50)
  - APM obituaries. 1974 (Box 108, Folder 51)
  - APM's books donated to the University of Arizona. 1976 (Box 108, Folder 52)